Guide to the Charles Morris Mount Papers MSS.497
Fales Library and Special Collections
Charles Morris Mount Papers
1980-2002
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mount, Charles Morris
Gordon, Harold
MSS.497
7.5 Linear Feet in 6 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 oversize flat box
Charles Morris Mount was an award-winning restaurant designer. Materials in the collection relate to Mount's work on numerous restaurant design projects and include menus, photographs, slides, transparencies, negatives, sketchbooks, design portfolios, newspaper clippings, correspondence, and awards. Materials date from 1980 to 2002.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Charles Morris Mount was an award-winning restaurant designer. Mount attended Auburn University in Auburn, Alabama where he earned his Bachelor of Interior Design degree. He then went on to study architecture and design at Écoles des Beaux-Arts, France. Mount continued to live in France for some time and spent a year studying cuisine at Cordon Bleu in Paris. Mount returned to the United States and started his career as a designer in Atlanta. Later moving to New York City, Mount served as Director of Interior Design at George Nelson & Company and eventually started his own architectural design firm, Charles Morris Mount Incorporated, in the early 1970’s. Mount designed nearly 300 restaurants in numerous locations across the United States and internationally. His designs won major awards including the Gold Key Award, IBD Design Award, The Lumen Award, Signs of the Times Competition, and Restaurants and Institutions Design Award.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Harold Gordon in March 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.048
Content Description
This collection contains the papers of restaurant designer Charles Morris Mount. Mount’s designs were created for restaurant buildings as well as the restaurants' interior decorations. Materials in the collection relate to Mount's work on numerous restaurant design projects and include menus, photographs, slides, transparencies, negatives, sketchbooks, design portfolios, newspaper clippings, correspondence, and awards. The collection also contains two reels labeled "The Evolution of the American Kitchen", and one CD labeled "McDonald's Times Sq." Materials date from 1980 to 2002.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Building designers; Interior decorators; Menus; Restaurants; Gordon, Harold
- Menus A-L, undated (Box 1)
- Restaurant Design Project Files, 1980-1995 (Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
- Menus M-Z, undated (Box 5)
- Unalphabetized Menus, undated (Box 5)
- Photographs, undated (Box 5)
- McDonald's Times Square CD, undated (Box 5)
- Design Portfolios, undated (Box 6)
- Du Pont Antron Design Award, 1989 (Box 6)
- Sketchbooks, 1984 (Box 6)
- Menus, undated (Box 7)
- Evolution of the American Kitchen Audio Reels, 1984 (Box 8)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1997-2002 (Box 8)
- University of the State of New York Interior Design Certificate, 2000 (Box 8)